ILGWU. Gus Tyler papers, 5780/088
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Series IV. Speaking Engagements, 1963-1981
  - Speaking Engagements (General), 1969 (Box 16, Folder 15)
    9/69-12/69.
  - Speaking Engagements (General), 1969-1970 (Box 16, Folder 16)
    12/69-4/70.
  - Speaking Engagements (General), 1970 (Box 16, Folder 17)
    4/70-6/70.
  - Speaking Engagements (General), 1970 (Box 16, Folder 18)
    7/70-12/70.
  - Speaking Engagements (General), 1971 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    1/71-8/71.
  - Speaking Engagements (General), 1971 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    9/71-11/71.
  - Speaking Engagements (General), 1971-1972 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    11/71-3/72.
  - Speaking Engagements (General), 1973-1972 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    3/73-7/72.
  - Speaking Engagements (General), 1972-1974 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    7/72-11/74.
  - Speaking Engagements (General), 1974-1975 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    11/74-5/75.
  - Speaking Engagements (General), 1975-1976 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    5/75-2/76.
  - Speaking Engagements (General), 1976 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    2/76-4/76.
  - Speaking Engagements (General), 1976-1977 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    4/76-5/77.
  - Speaking Engagements (General), 1977-1978 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    5/77-3/78.
  - Speaking Engagements (General), 1978 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Speaking Engagements (General), 1978 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    4/78-8/78.
  - Speaking Engagements (General), 1978-1979 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    9/78-4/79.
  - Speaking Engagements (General), 1979 (Box 17, Folder 14)
    4/79-7/79.
  - Speaking Engagements (General), 1979 (Box 17, Folder 15)
    7/79-10/79.
  - Speaking Engagements (General), 1979-1980 (Box 17, Folder 16)
    11/79-3/80.
  - Speaking Engagements (General), 1980 (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Speaking Engagements (General), 1980 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    8/80-10/80.
  - Speaking Engagements (General), 1980-1981 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    10/80-2/81.
  - Speaking Engagements (General), 1981 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    2/81-3/81.
  - Speaking Engagements (General), 1981 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    3/81-12/81.
  - American Jewish Committee, 1973-1974 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    9/73-1/74.
  - Boys' High Alumni Association, 1964 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    3/64-5/64.
  - Brookings Institution. General correspondence about seminars and conferences, 1964-1967 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    11/64-5/67.
  - Brookings Institution. General correspondence about seminars and conferences, 1967-1968 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    5/67-4/68.
  - Brookings Institution. General correspondence about seminars and conferences, 1968-1974 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    10/68-12/74.
  - Brookings Institution. General correspondence about seminars and conferences, 1975 (Box 18, Folder 10)
    1/75-11/75.
  - Brookings Institution. General correspondence about seminars and conferences, 1975-1976 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    11/75-11/76.
  - Brookings Institution. General correspondence about seminars and conferences, 1976-1977 (Box 18, Folder 12)
    11/76-2/77.
  - Brookings Institution. General correspondence about seminars and conferences, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 13)
    2/77-10/77.
  - Brookings Institution. General correspondence about seminars and conferences, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 14)
    10/77-11/77.
  - Brookings Institution. General correspondence about seminars and conferences, 1977-1978 (Box 18, Folder 15)
    11/77-7/78.
  - Brookings Institution. General correspondence about seminars and conferences, 1978-1979 (Box 18, Folder 16)
    8/78-10/79.
  - Brookings Institution. General correspondence about seminars and conferences, 1979-1981 (Box 18, Folder 17)
    10/79-12/81.
  - Brookings Institution. Lists of participants at seminars and conferences, 1978-1981 (Box 18, Folder 18)
    1/78-12/81.
  - Brookings Institution. Expenses, 1966-1974 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    10/66-12/74.
  - Brookings Institution. Expenses, 1974-1977 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    12/74-2/77.
  - Brookings Institution. Expenses, 1977-1981 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    3/77-12/81.
  - Center for Migration Studies, 1980 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Central Intelligence Agency (CIA), 1973-1980 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    2/73-5/80.
  - International Ladies' Garment Workers Union locals and joint boards, 1971-1975 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    11/71-9/75.
  - National Academy of Engineering, 1977 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    11/77-12/77.
  - United States Civil Service Commission, 1966-1970 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    11/66-8/70.
  - United States Civil Service Commission, 1970-1977 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    8/70-8/77.
  - United States Civil Service Commission, 1977-1978 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    8/77-11/78.
  - United States Office of Personnel Management (formerly United States Civil Service Commission), 1979- 1980 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    2/79-2/80.
  - United States Office of Personnel Management, 1980-1981 (Box 19, Folder 12)
    3/80-3/81.
  - United States Office of Personnel Management, 1981 (Box 19, Folder 13)
    3/81- 11/81.
  - United States State Department. [folder 1 of 2], 1973-1981 (Box 19, Folder 14)
    7/73-10/81.
  - United States State Department. [folder 2 of 2], 1973-1981 (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Western Electric, 1963-1971 (Box 19, Folder 16)
    12/63- 3/71.
  - Western Electric, 1971-1973 (Box 19, Folder 17)
    10/71- 11/73.
  - Western Electric, 1974-1977 (Box 19, Folder 18)
    1/74- 11/77.
- Series V. Columns, 1973-1982
  Contains series of columns written by Tyler for United Features Syndicate and later independently syndicated. Also includes correspondence with readers and editors. Primary subjects are politics, economics, taxes, labor, and current events.
  - Correspondence with readers and editors about columns, 1973-1974 (Box 19, Folder 19)
    6/73-4/74.
  - Correspondence with readers and editors about columns, 1974 (Box 19, Folder 20)
    4/74-7/74.
  - Correspondence with readers and editors about columns, 1974-1975 (Box 19, Folder 21)
    7/74-2/75.
  - Correspondence with readers and editors about columns, 1975 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    2/75-7/75.
  - Correspondence with readers and editors about columns, 1975 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    7/75-11/75.
  - Correspondence with readers and editors about columns, 1975-1976 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    11/75-3/76.
  - Correspondence with readers and editors about columns, 1976-1977 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    3/76-1/77.
  - Correspondence with readers and editors about columns, 1977 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    1/77-4/77.
  - Correspondence with readers and editors about columns, 1977-1978 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    4/77-5/78.
  - Correspondence with readers and editors about columns, 1978-1979 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    5/78-4/79.
  - Correspondence with readers and editors about columns, 1979-1980 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    5/79-5/80.
  - Correspondence with readers and editors about columns, 1980-1981 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    6/80-1/81.
  - Listing of United Features Syndicate columns 1-832, 1974-1979 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    1974-1979.
  - List of holds on United Features Syndicate columns (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - United Features Syndicate columns 30-125, 1974 (Box 20, Folder 12)
    3/74-10/74.
  - United Features Syndicate columns 126-207, 1974-1975 (Box 20, Folder 13)
    10/74-4/75.
  - United Features Syndicate columns 208-279, 1975 (Box 20, Folder 14)
    4/75- 10/75.
  - United Features Syndicate columns 280-361, 1975-1976 (Box 20, Folder 15)
    10/75-4/76.
  - United Features Syndicate columns 362-451, 1976 (Box 20, Folder 16)
    4/76- 11/76.
  - United Features Syndicate columns 452-534, 1976-1977 (Box 20, Folder 17)
    11/76-5/77.
  - United Features Syndicate columns 535-619, 1977 (Box 20, Folder 18)
    5/77- 12/77.
  - United Features Syndicate columns 620-692, 1977-1978 (Box 20, Folder 19)
    12/77-6/78.
  - United Features Syndicate columns 693-763, 1978 (Box 20, Folder 20)
    6/78- 11/78.
  - United Features Syndicate columns 764-832, 1978-1979 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    11/78-4/79.
  - Listing of independently syndicated columns 1-491, 1979-1982 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    1979-1982.
  - Independently syndicated columns 424-449, 1982 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    1/82-3/82.
  - Independently syndicated columns 450-481, 1982 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    3/82-5/82.
  - Independently syndicated columns 482-516, 1982 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    5/82-8/82.
  - Independently syndicated columns 517-581, 1982 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    8/82-12/82.
  - Miscellaneous writings, 1979-1980 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    6/79- 11/80.
- Series VI. Organized Crime in America, 1955-1966
  Files relating to Tyler's book, Organized Crime in America, published in 1962. The book is a collection of essays about crime edited by Tyler, and includes an introduction by Senator Estes Kefauver of Tennessee. Includes correspondence with contributors
  - General Correspondence, 1960-1962 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    1/60-4/62.
  - General Correspondence, 1962 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    4/62-5/62.
  - General Correspondence, 1962 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    5/62-6/62.
  - General Correspondence, 1962 (Box 21, Folder 11)
    6/62-10/62.
  - General Correspondence, 1962-1963 (Box 21, Folder 12)
    10/62-3/63.
  - General Correspondence, 1963-1966 (Box 21, Folder 13)
    3/63-3/66.
  - Book distribution, 1962 (Box 21, Folder 14)
    2/62-4/62.
  - Contemporary Affairs Society, 1962 (Box 21, Folder 15)
    4/62.
  - Reverend Joseph Fitzpatrick (contributor), 1961-1962 (Box 21, Folder 16)
    7/61-2/62.
  - Fund for the Republic, 1958-1960 (Box 21, Folder 17)
    11/58-10/60.
  - Mary Green, 1962 (Box 21, Folder 18)
    2/62-5/62.
  - Estes Kefauver (contributor), 1961-1962 (Box 21, Folder 19)
    10/61-2/62.
  - National Council on Crime and Delinquency, 1962-1963 (Box 21, Folder 20)
    3/62-1/63.
  - Promotion, 1962 (Box 21, Folder 21)
    3/62-5/62.
  - Requests for permission to use various pieces for the book. [folder 1 of 2], 1961-1964 (Box 21, Folder 22)
    3/61-4/64.
  - Requests for permission to use various pieces for the book. [folder 2 of 2], 1961-1964 (Box 21, Folder 23)
  - Royalties, 1962-1963 (Box 21, Folder 24)
    5/62-12/63.
  - University of Michigan Press (publisher), 1959-1961 (Box 21, Folder 25)
    11/59-4/61.
  - University of Michigan Press (publisher). [folder 1 of 2], 1961-1964 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    4/61-9/64.
  - University of Michigan Press (publisher). [folder 2 of 2], 1961-1964 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - General correspondence about special issue of the Annals of the American Academy of Political and Social Science on organized crime (Gus Tyler acting as special editor), 1962-1963 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    7/62-5/63.
  - Annals issue. Article manuscripts. [folder 1 of 2], 1963 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    2/63.
  - Annals issue. Article manuscripts. [folder 2 of 2], 1963 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Annals issue. Invitations to, and occasional declines of, potential writers, 1962 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    5/62-12/62.
  - Annals issue. Notes (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Annals issue. Correspondence with Louis J. Lefkowitz (contributor), 1962-1963 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    8/62-3/63.
  - Annals issue. Correspondence with Herbert J. Miller (contributor), 1962-1963 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    7/62-1/63.
  - Annals issue. Correspondence with Virgil W. Peterson (contributor), 1962-1963 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    9/62-6/63.
  - Annals issue. Correspondence with Dr. Thorsten Sellin, Annals editor, 1962-1963 (Box 22, Folder 11)
    5/62-5/63.
  - Annals issue. Correspondence with Dwight Strong (contributor), 1962-1963 (Box 22, Folder 12)
    9/62-1/63.
  - Annals issue. Correspondence with Robert Woetzel, 1962-1963 (Box 22, Folder 13)
    7/62-3/63.
  - Underworld Materials. File on action (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Underworld Materials. File on agreements between criminals and others, 1959-1961 (Box 22, Folder 15)
    8/59-8/61.
  - Underworld Materials. File on links to business, 1958-1959 (Box 22, Folder 16)
    12/58-9/59.
  - Underworld Materials. "Corruption in American Labor" (Box 22, Folder 17)
    Undated. Manuscript by John Hutchinson.
  - Underworld Materials. File on crime, 1955-1962 (Box 22, Folder 18)
    1955-5/62.
  - Underworld Materials. File on entertainment, 1959 (Box 22, Folder 19)
    12/59.
  - Underworld Materials. "A Fresh Appraisal of the Civil War", 1960 (Box 22, Folder 20)
    4/60. Article by D.W. Brogan.
  - Underworld Materials. File on gambling, 1959-1960 (Box 22, Folder 21)
    10/59-2/60.
  - Underworld Materials. File on gangs, 1959-1960 (Box 22, Folder 22)
  - Underworld Materials. File on investments, 1958-1959 (Box 22, Folder 23)
    10/58-8/59.
  - Underworld Materials. File on juvenile delinquency, 1960-1962 (Box 22, Folder 24)
    3/60-4/62.
  - Underworld Materials. File on links to labor, 1959-1960 (Box 22, Folder 25)
    6/59-3/60.
  - Underworld Materials. "Section 501(a) and the Proper Functions of Unions", 1959 (Box 22, Folder 26)
    Article by Gus Tyler.
  - Underworld Materials. United States Senate Select Committee on Improper Activities in the Labor or Management Field. Stenographic transcript of hearings, 1958 (Box 22, Folder 27)
    7/58.
  - Underworld Materials. Miscellaneous newspaper clippings, 1959-1964 (Box 22, Folder 28)
    8/59-4/64.
- Series VII. Miscellaneous Materials, 1962-1985
  - New Politics issue featuring Herbert Hill's article, "The ILGWU Today. The Decay of a Labor Union"; Tyler's response (manuscript); pamphlet, "Ethics for Everybody", by Richard R. Gilbert, 1962-1975 (Box 22, Folder 29)
    12/62-1975.
  - Dissent, fall 1983, fall 1984, spring 1985; The New Leader, December 24, 1984., 1983-1985 (Box 22, Folder 30)
    These publications contain articles by Tyler.
  - "A Union Story: Order Out of Chaos"; The Story of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (Box 22, Folder 31)
    Undated. Received from Gus Tyler
  - Northeast Department Staff Training Conference, 1969 (Box 23, Folder 30)
  - 1978 Imports (Box 24, Folder 1)
    Miscellaneous Articles
  - AFL-CIO Jobs and Trade Legislative Newsletter, 1973 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    (Vol.1, 1-20; April 2, 1973 - December 17, 1973) (Vol. 2, 1-8)
  - AFL-CIO Jobs and Trade Legislative Newsletter, 1973 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    Newsletters
  - AFL-CIO news articles on labor and world trade, 1976 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    Two activities from AFL CIO news (Dec. 18th and 25th - 1976) One article from N.Y. Daily News in sole of N.Y. magazine.
  - Americans for Democratic Action, 1978 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    Concerning 31st National Convention
  - Correspondence and campaign against Multinationals, 1972-1974 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    Gus Tyler - Speaker; Multinational Affairs
  - Correspondence on the issue of foreign imports, 1976-1977 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    Concerning foreign imports, Congressional records, and the Carter Administration
  - General Executive Board Report to the 39th Convention ILGWU, AFL-CIO CLC, 1986 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    Report Book
  - Imports - General, 1977-1978 (Box 24, Folder 9)
    Notes, newspaper clippings, and articles.
  - Imports - Rally, 1977 (Box 24, Folder 10)
    4/77. Suggested slogans, a flyer, and an article.
  - "Made in Hong Kong" ACTWU-ILGWU Flyer, 1977 (Box 24, Folder 11)
    Wall Street Journal article on the effects of importing textiles from Hong Kong.
  - "Multinationals: A Global Menace" and related correspondence, 1973-1977 (Box 24, Folder 12)
    An article by Gus Tyler
  - Multinational Multifiber Agreements, 1977 (Box 24, Folder 13)
    Newspaper clippings, memos, and flyers concerning trade and imports
  - Multinational Multifiber Agreements, 1977 (Box 24, Folder 14)
    Articles, memos, notes.
  - National Conference: American Labor's Stake and Voice in a Changing World Economy [Part 1 of 2] (Box 24, Folder 15)
    Volume 2
  - National Conference: American Labor's Stake and Voice in a Changing World Economy [Part 2 of 2] (Box 24, Folder 16)
  - Newspaper Clippings regarding Imports, 1977 (Box 24, Folder 17)
    Various copies of newspaper clippings.
  - "Trade vs. Jobs", 1977 (Box 24, Folder 18)
    Copies of an article called "Trade vs. Jobs" in the Congressional Record newsletter; concerns imports.
  - Transfer of Technology, 1977 (Box 24, Folder 19)
    Sending, list, copy.
  - "Viewpoint", 1977 (Box 24, Folder 20)
    Various magazine issues of "Viewpoint".